Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a lesson for you all about life at home and life with
我是Catherine，今天我们有一节课，内容是关于家庭生活和与
your parents.
父母同住的生活。
That's right.
没错。
We've all lived with our parents when we were younger or maybe we still do and of course
我们年轻时都曾和父母住过，或者可能现在还住在一起，当然
they have certain rules in the house and well, when you break those rules, something happens.
家里有某些规矩，当你违反这些规矩时，就会发生一些事。
There are consequences and that's what's happening in today's dialogue.
会有后果，这就是今天对话中发生的情况。
So let's take a listen to this dialogue and when we come back, we'll be talking more about
所以让我们听听这段对话，回来后我们会进一步讨论
what's going on and what some of these words and phrases mean.
发生了什么，以及这些单词和短语的含义。
Do you know what time it is?
你知道现在几点了吗？
Um, ten.
嗯，十点。
Get in this door, young man.
给我进来，年轻人。
It's midnight.
现在是午夜。
You are two hours past curfew.
你晚归了两个小时。
I know, but it wasn't my fault.
我知道，但这不是我的错。
I told Jennifer she had to drop me off before ten, but she wouldn't leave the party.
我告诉Jennifer她必须在十点前送我回来，但她不肯离开派对。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
You are grounded for life, mister.
你被禁足了，一辈子，先生。
Mom, that is so unfair.
妈，这太不公平了。
You know the rules and you broke them.
你知道规矩，你违反了它们。
No allowance and no TV for a week.
一周没有零花钱，也不准看电视。
I usually never ground you, but this time I have to put my foot down.
我通常从不禁足你，但这次我必须坚决一点。
What?
什么？
For being a couple of hours late?
就为了晚回来几个小时？
You have to be kidding.
你一定是在开玩笑。
I don't want to hear it.
我不想听。
Now go to your room.
现在回你房间去。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very typical case, somebody or the kid returns home, it's too late and now they're
一个非常典型的情况，有人或孩子回家晚了，现在他们
in trouble.
有麻烦了。
Yes, his parents are not very happy.
是的，他的父母不太高兴。
In this case, it's his mom who is telling him what the consequences will be.
在这个例子中，是他妈妈在告诉他后果是什么。
So let's take a look at Language Takeaway and find out what some of these key words
所以让我们看看“语言要点”部分，找出这些关键词
are.
是什么。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so the first word that we're going to take a look is actually something that
好的，我们要看的第一个词实际上是他妈妈说的，
his mom said and he said that you are two hours past curfew.
她说你晚归了两个小时。
Curfew.
晚归时间。
So curfew has to do specifically with the time when your parents expect you at home.
所以“curfew”特指父母期望你到家的时间。
That's right.
没错。
So if your curfew is ten o'clock, you have to be home before or by ten o'clock.
所以如果你的晚归时间是十点，你必须在十点之前或十点到家。
Right.
对。
So in this case, if the boy's curfew is ten o'clock and he arrives home at midnight, twelve
所以在这个例子中，如果男孩的晚归时间是十点，而他午夜十二点到家，
o'clock, he's two hours past curfew.
他就晚归了两个小时。
That's right.
没错。
And even sometimes cities or governments will implement certain curfews at certain times.
有时城市或政府也会在特定时间实施某些宵禁。
That's right.
没错。
And I don't think adults really have curfews at home.
而且我认为成年人家里通常没有晚归时间。
No, I don't think so.
不，我不这么认为。
It depends on what you want, but kids definitely have curfews.
这取决于你想要什么，但孩子肯定有晚归时间。
What happens though, Marco, when you break curfew?
那么，Marco，违反晚归时间会发生什么？
So this is a very serious offense and you're going to get punished.
这是一个非常严重的违规行为，你会受到惩罚。
And the way that we say this, usually parents to their children, you are grounded or you
我们通常这样说，父母对孩子说，你被禁足了，或者
ground that kid.
禁足那个孩子。
Okay.
好的。
So you might have heard this word when talking about airplanes or flights at an airport.
你可能在谈论飞机或机场航班时听过这个词。
The plane was grounded.
飞机被停飞了。
It basically means it can't go anywhere.
它基本上意味着不能去任何地方。
And so when you're talking about a kid or a person, you basically mean, okay, you're
所以当谈论孩子或人时，你基本上是说，好吧，你
grounded, you can't go out with your friends.
被禁足了，不能和朋友出去。
You can't go anywhere.
你不能去任何地方。
Usually you can go to school.
通常你可以去上学。
Right, right.
对，对。
But you can't have fun is the meaning.
但你不能玩，就是这个意思。
That's right.
没错。
So it's usually a fixed phrase.
所以这通常是一个固定短语。
You're grounded.
你被禁足了。
That means that you are punished.
这意味着你被惩罚了。
You can't go out.
你不能出去。
But in this case, the mom specified saying you're grounded.
但在这个例子中，妈妈明确说了你被禁足了。
So that means that he can't go out.
所以这意味着他不能出去。
But on top of that, she said no allowance and no TV for a week.
但除此之外，她还说一周没有零花钱，也不准看电视。
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
So allowance is the money that your parents give you to go out, like to go to the movies
所以“allowance”是父母给你的钱，让你出去，比如看电影
or something.
之类的。
And your parents might give this to you on a weekly basis.
你的父母可能每周给你一次。
So every Saturday you get $5 or on a monthly basis, every month you get $20.
所以每个星期六你得到5美元，或者每月一次，每个月你得到20美元。
And when his mother says you're not going to have any allowance for a week, that means
当他妈妈说一周没有零花钱时，这意味着
we're not going to give you any money this week.
这周我们不会给你任何钱。
That's right.
没错。
So that is an allowance, how much money you get per month or per week.
所以那就是零花钱，你每个月或每周得到的钱。
The key thing about allowance though, is that it's not something you do for work.
不过零花钱的关键在于，它不是因为你工作而得到的。
You don't work and receive allowance.
你工作不会得到零花钱。
If you work, you have a salary.
如果你工作，你会有薪水。
Allowance is something that you get for free from someone.
零花钱是你从别人那里免费得到的东西。
So you can get an allowance from your boss to eat, but you can also have an allowance
所以你可以从老板那里得到零花钱来吃饭，但你也可以从父母那里得到零花钱
from your parents to do fun things.
来做有趣的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So usually kids, obviously they can't work, so they get an allowance from their parents,
所以通常孩子们，显然他们不能工作，所以他们从父母那里得到零花钱，
usually for fun things like going to the movies and stuff.
通常用于有趣的事情，比如看电影之类的。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好了。
Now, going back a little bit, let's take a look at two ways that the mom addressed or
现在，稍微回顾一下，让我们看看妈妈称呼或叫儿子的两种方式，
called her son, because obviously it's her son.
因为显然那是她的儿子。
But when he got home, she said, get in this door, young man.
但当他回家时，她说，给我进门，年轻人。
Okay.
好的。
So, angry mom phrases.
所以，这是生气妈妈用语。
When you're in trouble, your parents tend to use different words to talk to you.
当你惹上麻烦时，你的父母往往会用不同的词语跟你说话。
So this is a very popular one, young man.
所以这是一个非常流行的说法，年轻人。
So it's like saying, you should be mature, but you made a mistake.
这就像在说，你应该成熟，但你犯了错。
All right.
好了。
So, come inside right now, young man.
所以，马上进来，年轻人。
It's a way to emphasize that you are also very angry.
这是一种强调你也很生气的方式。
And also, when he was trying to explain what happened, she said, I don't care.
还有，当他试图解释发生了什么时，她说，我不在乎。
You're grounded for life, mister.
你被禁足一辈子了，先生。
So these are both ways of talking to young boys.
所以这些都是对小男孩说话的方式。
Mister is the opposite of miss.
Mister 是 miss 的反义词。
But in the case of a young girl, you'd say, get in this door, young lady.
但如果是小女孩，你会说，给我进门，年轻女士。
Right.
对。
And then, you're grounded for life, missy.
然后，你被禁足一辈子了，小姐。
Missy.
小姐。
Yeah, I think they say missy.
是的，我觉得他们会说小姐。
Missy.
小姐。
So, missy, mister, young man, young lady.
所以，小姐、先生、年轻人、年轻女士。
These are all ways of referring to people in kind of, it's weird.
这些都是称呼人的方式，有点奇怪。
It's kind of like they're adults, but they're not.
这有点像他们是成年人，但他们又不是。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
That's like saying, you're in trouble.
这就像在说，你惹上麻烦了。
Yeah.
是的。
So, very interesting things going on here with this young man who got grounded.
所以，这个被禁足的年轻人身上发生了很有趣的事情。
Why don't we go back, let's take a look at our dialogue again, and we'll be back in a
我们为什么不回去，再看一遍我们的对话，我们一会儿回来。
bit.
一会儿。
Do you know what time it is?
你知道现在几点了吗？
10.
10点。
Get in this door, young man.
给我进门，年轻人。
It's midnight.
现在是午夜。
You are two hours past curfew.
你超过宵禁时间两个小时了。
I know, but it wasn't my fault.
我知道，但这不是我的错。
I told Jennifer she had to drop me off before 10, but she wouldn't leave the party.
我告诉詹妮弗她必须在10点前送我回家，但她不肯离开派对。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
You are grounded for life, mister.
你被禁足一辈子了，先生。
Mom, that is so unfair.
妈妈，这太不公平了。
You know the rules, and you broke them.
你知道规矩，而且你违反了它们。
No allowance and no TV for a week.
一周没有零花钱，没有电视。
I usually never ground you, but this time I have to put my foot down.
我通常从不禁足你，但这次我必须坚决一点。
What?
什么？
You're being a couple of hours late?
你只是晚了一两个小时？
You have to be kidding.
你一定是在开玩笑。
I don't want to hear it.
我不想听。
Now, go to your room.
现在，回你房间去。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, now let's take a look at four key phrases that we've picked out for you on Fluency Builder.
所以，现在让我们看看我们在流利度构建器中为你挑选的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right.
好了。
So, this first phrase is something that actually we hear when the young boy or the young man
所以，第一个短语实际上是我们听到那个小男孩或年轻人
is giving his excuse for being late.
在为自己的迟到找借口时说的。
He said, listen, I told Jennifer she had to drop me off before 10.
他说，听着，我告诉詹妮弗她必须在10点前送我回家。
That's right.
没错。
So, the phrasal verb there is to drop off.
所以，那里的短语动词是 drop off。
This means to leave someone somewhere.
这意味着把某人留在某个地方。
That's right.
没错。
But usually it means to drive someone to a certain place.
但通常它意味着开车送某人到某个地方。
So, for example, Jennifer probably has a car, and Jennifer was supposed to take this boy
所以，例如，詹妮弗可能有车，詹妮弗应该送这个男孩回家，
home, so he said she was going to drop me off before 10 o'clock.
所以他说她会在10点前送我回家。
That means kind of leave him at his house.
这意味着把他留在他家。
That's right.
没错。
The verb is to drop off, but we usually insert the subject in between it.
动词是 drop off，但我们通常把主语插在中间。
So, to drop me off.
所以，是 drop me off。
She is going to drop me off.
她打算开车送我一程。
I dropped him off at the bank.
我把他送到了银行。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So, now that Jennifer was supposed to drop him off at 10, that didn't happen, so he got
所以，詹妮弗本应在10点送他，但没发生，所以他被禁足了。
grounded and his mom was saying that she usually doesn't really ground him, but this time I
他妈妈说她通常不会真的禁足他，但这次我
have to put my foot down.
必须坚决一点。
She's angry.
她很生气。
Yeah.
是啊。
He's upset and she's angry and she said, listen, I have to put my foot down.
他很难过，她很生气，她说，听着，我必须坚决一点。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
You put your foot on the ground?
你把脚踩在地上？
It's strange to hear this phrase.
听到这个短语很奇怪。
It means that she's going to be strict, that she's not going to let him just get away with
意思是她会很严格，不会让他轻易逃脱
it or not ground him.
或者不禁足他。
She really has to be strict and she has to punish him.
她真的必须严格，必须惩罚他。
Okay.
好的。
So, to put your foot down or I put my foot down, this means to be strict with someone,
所以，“put your foot down”或“I put my foot down”意思是对某人严格，
to not maybe bend the rules or be flexible.
不轻易通融或灵活处理。
So, for example, my mother was always very, very loose with my brother.
比如，我妈妈对我哥哥一直非常宽松。
He could do what he wanted or whatever, but one day he did something really horrible and
他想做什么就做什么，但有一天他做了非常糟糕的事，
she finally put her foot down.
她终于坚决起来了。
And she grounded him.
然后她禁足了他。
She grounded him for three months.
她禁足了他三个月。
Alright.
好的。
So, that's what happens when somebody puts their foot down.
所以，这就是当某人坚决起来时发生的事。
And now, obviously, he was very surprised that he's going to be grounded for so long
现在，显然，他非常惊讶自己会被禁足这么久，
and only for being a couple of hours late.
仅仅因为晚到了几个小时。
So, he said, you have to be kidding.
所以，他说，你一定是在开玩笑。
You have got to be kidding.
你一定是在开玩笑。
So, this is a rhetorical.
这是个反问句。
So, he's not talking about joking here.
所以，他不是在说开玩笑的事。
He's saying, no way.
他在说，不可能。
I can't believe it.
我无法相信。
This is not happening to me.
这不可能发生在我身上。
Yeah.
是啊。
You're not serious.
你不是认真的吧。
And I would be too.
我也会这样。
No one likes to be grounded.
没人喜欢被禁足。
But he's saying, okay, come on.
但他说，好吧，拜托。
No way.
不可能。
That's too serious.
那太严重了。
That's right.
没错。
So, this is a phrase that you can use with someone if you're not really believing what
所以，这是一个你可以对某人用的短语，如果你不太相信
they're saying or you're surprised.
他们说的话，或者你很惊讶。
You have to be kidding me.
你一定是在跟我开玩笑。
Yeah.
是啊。
But usually, there's also a degree of anger.
但通常，也带有一点愤怒。
So, you're upset at the decision.
所以，你对这个决定感到不满。
For example, I'm watching the World Cup right now and there was a foul.
比如，我现在在看世界杯，有一个犯规。
And I was very upset because I didn't think it was a foul and I said, you have got to
我非常不满，因为我觉得那不是犯规，我说，你一定是在
be kidding me.
跟我开玩笑。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, that's exactly the way that we would use that phrase.
所以，这正是我们使用那个短语的方式。
And well, obviously, the mother had made up her mind.
而且，显然，妈妈已经下定决心了。
She's very decided.
她非常坚决。
And she said, I don't want to hear it.
她说，我不想听。
So, this is the end of the conversation.
所以，这就是对话的结束。
Okay.
好的。
This is one of those phrases that will just stop anything you're talking about.
这是那种会直接打断你任何谈话的短语之一。
So, they're arguing and she says, nope, I don't want to hear it.
所以，他们在争吵，她说，不，我不想听。
That means no more excuses.
意思是别再找借口了。
No more talking.
别再说话了。
This is the end.
到此为止。
That's right.
没错。
I don't want to hear it.
我不想听。
And it's used in many scenarios, right?
而且它在很多场景中都会用到，对吧？
Not only for somebody being angry or grounded, but also in a meeting.
不仅用于某人生气或被禁足，也用于会议中。
I don't want to hear it.
我不想听。
That's it.
就这样。
We're doing my idea.
我们按我的想法来。
We're going forward with it.
我们继续推进。
Well, be careful because that's usually what the boss will say.
嗯，要小心，因为通常老板会这么说。
That's right.
没错。
It's not the most gentle phrase.
这不是最温和的短语。
And so, you have to be careful with how you use it.
所以，你使用它时要小心。
But if you have authority like you're a parent or you're a boss, you can say, nope, I don't
但如果你有权威，比如你是家长或老板，你可以说，不，我
want to hear it.
不想听。
I have made my decision.
我已经做了决定。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, we've taken a look at a lot of great things.
那么，我们看了很多很棒的东西。
Why don't we go back, listen to our dialogue one last time.
我们不如回去，再听一遍我们的对话。
We'll be back in a bit.
我们一会儿就回来。
Do you know what time it is?
你知道现在几点了吗？
10.
十点。
Get in this door, young man.
给我进门来，年轻人。
It's midnight.
现在是午夜。
You are two hours past curfew.
你晚回家两个小时。
I know, but it wasn't my fault.
我知道，但这不是我的错。
I told Jennifer she had to drop me off before 10, but she wouldn't leave the party.
我告诉詹妮弗她必须在十点前送我回来，但她不肯离开派对。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
You are grounded for life, mister.
你被禁足了，一辈子，先生。
Mom, that is so unfair.
妈，这太不公平了。
You know the rules and you broke them.
你知道规矩，你违反了它们。
No allowance and no TV for a week.
一周没有零花钱，也不能看电视。
I usually never ground you, but this time I have to put my foot down.
我通常从不禁足你，但这次我必须坚决一点。
What?
什么？
For being a couple of hours late?
就为了晚回家几个小时？
You have to be kidding.
你一定是在开玩笑。
I don't want to hear it.
我不想听。
Now go to your room.
现在回你房间去。
All right.
好吧。
We're back.
我们回来了。
We've all been grounded.
我们都被禁足过。
What is the longest you've been grounded for?
你被禁足最长时间是多久？
Do you remember?
你还记得吗？
I was a good girl, so maybe a week.
我是个乖女孩，所以大概一周吧。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, maybe not even.
是啊，可能还不到一周。
I never really got in trouble as a kid.
我小时候几乎没惹过麻烦。
What about you?
你呢？
I think once I was grounded the entire summer.
我想有一次我被禁足了整个夏天。
Oh, rough.
哦，真惨。
Yeah, the entire summer vacation.
是啊，整个暑假。
I don't remember exactly what I did, but my dad was pretty upset with me and yeah,
我不太记得具体做了什么，但我爸当时对我很生气，然后，
he was really strict, so I got grounded quite a bit.
他真的很严格，所以我被禁足过好几次。
I tend to think that girls get in trouble less.
我倾向于认为女孩惹的麻烦少一些。
I think so.
我也这么觉得。
I don't know if it's because they're good.
我不知道是不是因为她们乖。
I think probably it's because they're better at hiding things from their parents.
我想可能是因为她们更擅长对父母隐瞒事情。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Because whenever I would come home, my mother would always wake up, but she doesn't really
因为每次我回家，我妈总会醒来，但她不太
understand what time it is, and so I'd say, oh, mom, it's 11 o'clock.
知道现在几点，所以我就说，哦，妈，现在十一点了。
Good night.
晚安。
And it'd be like 4 o'clock in the morning, and she had no idea.
而实际上可能是凌晨四点，她完全不知道。
So who was the person or the parent that put their foot down?
那么，是谁，或者说哪个家长，坚决执行了规矩？
Was it your mom or your dad?
是你妈妈还是你爸爸？
My dad was the serious one.
我爸是那个严肃的人。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah, it's interesting because sometimes it's the dad that's very strict, and the mom kind
是啊，这很有趣，因为有时候是爸爸很严格，而妈妈会
of helps you out and tries to kind of not get you grounded or something, but sometimes
帮你一把，试图让你不被禁足之类的，但有时候
it's the other way around.
情况正好相反。
The mom is really strict and firm, and the dad's like, come on, don't ground him.
妈妈非常严格和坚定，而爸爸会说，别禁足他了。
They're just having fun.
他们只是在玩而已。
Well, I think in some families, the children understand who is strict and who is maybe
嗯，我觉得在一些家庭里，孩子们知道谁严格，谁可能
not so strict, and so they say, oh, well, mom said that it's okay, so I think maybe
不那么严格，所以他们就说，哦，妈妈说了可以，所以我觉得也许
you should let me go out, and the dad will be very angry because the mother said that
你应该让我出去，然后爸爸会很生气，因为妈妈说了
it's okay.
可以。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so that's all the time we have for today.
好了，今天的时间就到这里。
We're really curious to get your stories, maybe tell us why were you grounded or how
我们很好奇想听听你们的故事，也许告诉我们你为什么被禁足，或者
long were you grounded for?
你被禁足了多久？
Or what was your curfew when you were a child or growing up?
或者你小时候或成长过程中的宵禁时间是什么？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。
Well, see you guys there.
嗯，我们会在那里见你们。